Software Programmer

ROHITH REDDY

rohithreddyt@yandex.com

+91 888 654 0155

rohithreddy.github.io

೧ rohithreddy

EXPERIENCE

N!yo

Data Engineer | June 2017 - April 2018

RedBlackTree

Serverside IOT Engineer | October 2016 - February 2017

Sphota Biz

Member of Technical Staff | September 2018 - August 2019

Customer Centria

Full-stack Developer | July 2015 - August 2016

Created campaign analytics dashboard in Backbone.js Single Page Application, integrating d3.js and nvd3.js libraries into Omni-channel Campaign management SaaS product, wrote REST API's for aggregating statistics from campaigns with Spring and MongoDB

Used Jenkins to create a CI / CD pipeline and automated reliable deployments
Proposed and managed a Mesos cluster for running applications and data workloads, increasing developer productivity making deployments more resilient and manageable
Implemented a resilient pipeline to capture tweets based on keywords related to clients & perform sentiment analysis for a customer 360 data application with help from data scientists, senior developers. Used Kafka, Python, MongoDB running on the Mesos Cluster

EDUCATION

Major in Physics with Honors, BITS Pilani University, India

Master of Science | August 2009 - March 2015

SKILLS

About me

A Programmer with 4+ years of experience in building Data Intensive Applications that are simple and functional, tackling challenging architectural and scalability problems. In my free time I am either hacking Linux kernel or building embedded IoT devices.